Welcome to Motif.
My name is Thomas.
Here we will be learning how to use the custom
audiences and the lookalike audiences that we've just created.
So we will go to create.
We will always use these for conversion adverts.
So go ahead and select that.
We want to make sure the
campaign budget optimization is turned off.
Here it is.
We will then select the ad set.
We will then select the Pixel that we
want to use is this Pixel and we
will select the conversion event of purchase.
Now you will notice that on this account,
as this is just an example, I haven't
actually sold anything on this Pixel.
So it's read it out, it's red.
Normally you won't see that.
Normally it will be green if you've had purchases.
But nonetheless, we can still explain and
show how custom audiences are used.
So if we click here, you will get a list
of all of the custom audiences that we've just created.
So here's the view content for the campaign in the
last three days if you're using a lookalike audience.
So let's select the lookalike audience United States.
Now we will see that it says
the potential reaches fewer than 1000 people.
It probably hasn't built that audience yet.
And also crucially, I have set my location to
the United Kingdom, whereas this is US United States.
So the first thing to do is to make
sure that you're running to people living in this
location and then browse and then go to countries.
And for this one we would Select United States.
We turn off United Kingdom and it
has compiled the audience 2 million people.
I normally leave this for the
lookalike audiences because Facebook is already
determining what it likes to see.
However, don't forget if you are running anything related to
alcohol or anything adult at all, it's always best to
go to 22 because the legal drinking age is 21.
Check this because each country is different.
Some countries, some Scandinavian countries is
completely prohibited to advertise some things.
Every country in the world will
have different things that are prohibited.
So make sure that you know exactly what the rules are.
It's all in the advertising guidelines on Facebook.
I will still change the placements,
especially for a look alike.
I will remove desktop and I will
remove all of these other placements.
Easy way of doing it.
There is to click there, remove them all
and then add back in Facebook newsfeed, which
is the one that we want.
Everything else is not so good.
So that is the basic you see that
the audience reaches dropped down to 1.4 million
now because we have selected only Facebook newsfeed
and people living only in the United States.
That's how you would set up for a
lookalike audience and you would set the budget
in the same way that you normally do.
So whether you're running at $5 or
whatever, $10, it's all done here.
You can select that I always
start the advert the next day.
My advert account is set to Pacific Time
even though I'm in the United Kingdom.
So wherever you're always set to the next
day at midnight, you can choose this when
you first set up the ad account.
After that, you can't change it.
Eastern Time is meant to be quite a good
one to pick, although I haven't tested them all.
Pacific Time seems to work well for me.
Please pick whatever you want if
you haven't already selected one.
If you have, then you can't change it.
So I wouldn't worry about things that you can't worry
about or change where you worry about them, but you
can't change them, so don't worry about them.
And that is very simply how you
would select to use a lookalike audience.
And that is it.
For a custom audience, it's exactly the same.
So let's discard drafts because I'm
not going to run anything.
I'm just showing how it works.
So it'd be conversions, correct.
We go into the ad set, we select purchase.
You can try add to cart.
I always run to purchase, even if it's in red,
which it wouldn't be if you're running an advert account.
This is just because this is a dummy Pixel, for example,
on an advert account that I don't use very often.
Now for retargeting, we will set the budget quite low.
You can go as low as one dollars
a day, anything between one and $5 depending
on how big you think the audience is. $2.
$50 is something I often use here.
Okay.
Next day, midnight.
Now in the custom audiences, this time we'll select
custom audience and we will select everybody that has
viewed the content, viewed the campaign name.
So this would be everybody that had viewed a campaign.
So I would have selected the campaign URL
name there in the last 30 days.
And now the powerful part, if we
exclude we exclude everybody that's purchased.
So everybody that's viewed you'd set up
the name, this would be your product.
Excluding everybody that's purchased.
That's how you set it up.
Exclude the people that have purchased that
campaign in the last 30 days.
Now you can run to view content.
We've covered all of this.
You can do three day, five day.
You can include an offer.
But the targeting, this is how it's all set up.
I normally leave this completely wide open.
And because this is retargeting, I
often leave the placement on automatic.
So it will be shown across everywhere that
it can be shown because they've already clicked.
They've already clicked on my product.
Now that's how I would set
up that's a campaign retargeting.
So this ad and add to this one.
This product would already be running and I would
be excluding the people that had bought and retargeting
the people that are viewed but not purchased.
Now, what you can also do is remove these so that
one I would normally start running you'd make the advert but
here I would want to re target everybody that's engaged with
my page over the last 365 days and the way that
I would do that is I select that there I could
exclude the people that have purchased the product that I'm running
to let's do that so that's everybody that has engaged in
any way with my page in the last 365 days Excluding
everybody that had purchased the item in question the campaign in
question location UK what I want to do here is I
would change this to worldwide so that everybody that has Let
me see if this will have to remove it select all right.
Worldwide people living worldwide everybody in the world that
has engaged with my page now I will change
it to manual placements because I like only Facebook
newsfeed on mobile you can test other placements of
course but when I first started out I always
run to this unless it's a retargeting of people
that have at least viewed the content so that's
how this would be done turn these off okay.
Ignore all of this just leave it
in default don't mess with it.
You can test different settings down there but I just leave
it I wouldn't worry now we're worldwide everyone in the world
Zoom out there we are everyone that's engaged with your page
and we want to set the budget here a little higher
because depending on the size of the audience that you've got
So I would say somewhere around $5 normally works depending on
how big your audience is it's not showing me the audience
here Because this is just a dummy audience that I set
up for a page that I'm not using and that's exactly
how it'd be done.
Your conversion event is still purchased and you're targeting
everybody that is engaged with your page Excluding everybody
that had purchased the campaign in the last 180
days so go back and watch the other video
on how to set up custom audiences which is
in the training course. Okay. Excellent.
Thank you very much.